http://www.mdfoodbank.org/privacy-policy/

Open Menu
Welcome to the Maryland Food Bank, a website located at mdfoodbank.org (the Site). The Site is owned by The Maryland Food Bank, Inc., a Maryland corporation (referred to herein as us, we, our, or the Food Bank). Collectively, all visitors to the Site are referred to herein as you or user.
Please read this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use before you access, use, or provide any information to the Site. This Privacy Policy incorporates the Terms of Use by reference. By using the Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, then you do not have permission to access, use, or submit information to the Site.
The Food Bank respects your privacy. We created this Privacy Policy to explain why we collect certain information and how we will protect your personal privacy within the Site. The information we collect from you may include information, such as your name, postal address, email address, phone number, or any other identifier by which you may be contacted online or offline (collectively, Personal Information) as well as other information that does not identify you as an individual person. We value your trust and appreciate your important sponsorship. If you have any questions or comments concerning our privacy practices, please contact us. Our contact information is listed in the section headed “Contact us” below.
What information we collect
Information you voluntarily provide
We collect information, including Personal Information, from you when you voluntarily provide such information. For example, if you register as a partner or volunteer with the Food Bank, provide a donation to the Food Bank, or submit an inquiry to the Site, we may collect your name, contact information, and location.
Sensitive information
We ask that you not send or otherwise disclose sensitive information to us about your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background, or trade union membership, unless we specifically request such sensitive information. If you provide sensitive information to us without our request, then we may delete any such sensitive information.
Children
The Site is not intended for individuals under the age of 13, and the Food Bank does not knowingly collect information from such individuals. We may delete any information identified as being provided by individuals under the age of 13.
Server logs
The servers we use to host the Site collect certain log information about your use of the Site. This log information consists of the typical information collected when a server hosts a website over the Internet, such as the internet protocol (IP) address assigned to your device, the date and time the Site was requested, and the previous webpage you visited. Depending on the configuration of your connection to the Internet, your IP address may provide an indication of your location, which is generally no more precise than the city where your device is located.
Internet browser and device services
The internet browser you use to access the Site collects and provides us certain information about your device. Depending on your browser, this information can include the type of device you use, your operating system type and version, and browser type and version. Services running on your device may provide us information about you. For example, geolocation services running on your device may provide address-level location data to us.
Cookies
Like most websites, we use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies (collectively, Cookies) to track your usage of the Site. Cookies are small files that can be issued to your device when you visit a website or use a mobile application, or that can be embedded in the content of an email, webpage, or application. Depending on their purpose, some Cookies may expire when you close your internet browser or your mobile application, and other Cookies may remain stored on your device for a longer period of time. We use Cookies to track your access to the Site, your usage of different features of the Site, your usage of other websites or mobile applications, and to track whether you click links or access certain content that we provide to you on the Site or in communications to you.
We may directly set Cookies to your device or a third party may set cookies to your device through the Site. For example, we may contract with third party service providers, to process your data and analyze usage patterns on the Site. We currently work with the following third party service providers:
Google Analytics
Facebook
LinkedIn
Active Campaign
MailChimp
By accepting this Privacy Policy, you consent to the processing of your information by these third party service providers. The protection of information collected by these third party service providers is governed by their privacy policies and related terms. Please visit their websites to review such privacy policies and related terms.
Limiting Collection
Most internet browsers, mobile applications, and operating systems allow you to configure privacy settings to limit or disable cookies, web beacons, and related technologies. For example, you can typically adjust settings to cause a browser to notify you when a cookie has been issued or to block cookies altogether. You can also generally disable services running on your device, such as geolocation services. Certain internet browsers may enable you to request that websites “do not track” your browsing behavior on the website. The Site currently does not respond to such “do not track” signals because there is no consistent industry standard for compliance with such signals. For more information privacy settings and configuring cookies, web beacons, and related technologies please see aboutads.info/choices.
Although you are under no obligation to provide us with information, certain information we collect is necessary for the functionality of the Site. Should you choose to withhold certain information, we may not be able to provide you with access to or use of some features of the Site.
How we use your information
Our use
We use information we collect from you for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise described at the point such information is collected. Generally, we use the Personal Information we collect from you for the purpose it was collected. For example:
when your provide Personal Information when registering as a partner or volunteer with the Food Bank, providing a donation to the Food Bank, or submitting an inquiry to the Site, we will use such Personal Information to process your registration, register your donation, and respond to your inquiry, respectively.
We may use Personal Information we collect from you to ensure the security, maintenance, and improvement of the Site, to operate the Food Bank’s business, and to market relevant services to you. For example, we may use Personal Information we collect:
to enhance access to and presentation of the features of the Site and customize content for your experience;
to alert you about features or changes to the Site and other services of the Food Bank;
to update and enforce this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, and other contracts;
to comply with applicable laws;
to protect the Food Bank’s business, our rights, and those of our users;
to evaluate the satisfaction of our users with the Site;
to identify the number of unique visitors to the Site, determine how long you access certain content on the Site, and determine how frequently you use certain features; and
to conduct research on the behaviors, interests, and demographics of our users.
We may use any information we collect from you that is not Personal Information, for any purpose.
Use by third parties
The third party service providers we work with may use Cookies to collect information about your online activities over time and on other websites, and may use such information to target advertising to you on the Site and on other websites and mobile applications.
Disclosure of your information
Protection of your information
The Food Bank will not, subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy, intentionally disclose Personal Information we collect from you to third parties without your consent.
General disclosure
We may disclose the Personal Information we collect from you in accordance with Privacy Policy or as described to you at the point your Personal Information is collected.
Specifically, we may disclose your Personal Information to:
affiliate organizations;
third parties that are non-profit organizations with charitable purposes similar to the Food Bank’s;
third parties in connection with a reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, or other disposition of all or substantially all of the Food Bank’s business; or
third parties that provide services to the Food Bank related to the Site.
Any such third party has represented to the Food Bank that it maintains reasonable confidentiality protections for your Personal Information.
Unconditional disclosure
In addition, we may disclose your Personal Information unconditionally:
to law enforcement authorities or other government officials;
when we believe disclosure is reasonably appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss; or
in connection with an investigation of illegal activity.
We may disclose any information we collect from you that is not Personal Information, to any third party, for any purpose.
Links
The Site may contain links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another site for which the Food Bank has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy policies and terms on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.
Where your information is processed
The information the Food Bank directly collects is processed and stored in the United States. The information collected using Cookies set by third party service providers identified in this Privacy Policy may or may not be processed in the United States. Please review the privacy policies and related terms of such third party service providers to determine the location of their processing activities.
Security
The Food Bank will take reasonable steps to prevent the unauthorized disclosure or use of the Personal Information we process or store. However, no transmission of information over the Internet is fully secure.
Retention
In general, the Food Bank retains your Personal Information for as long as it is relevant for the purposes it was collected, unless a longer period of time is required to comply with our record retention policy, to protect ourselves against legal claims, or to comply with applicable laws.
Your rights
In general
If you would not like us to share your Personal Information with third parties that are non-profit organizations with charitable purposes similar to the Food Bank’s, please contact us with your request using the contact information listed in the section headed “Contact us” below.
If you are in California
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us with your request using the contact information indicated in “Contact us” below. If you would like a response via email, please include an email address. Otherwise, we will respond by postal mail within the time required by law.
Consent
By using the Site, you consent to the collection, use, disclosure, and storage of your information by us in the manner described in this Privacy Policy or at the point such information was collected.
Changes
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy on this location of the Site. If you object to any changes, you may stop using the Site. Continuing to access or use the Site after we publish changes to this Privacy Policy means that you agree to the changes, subject to applicable law.
Contact us
If you have questions or requests concerning this Privacy Policy, please contact the Food Bank by email at info@mdfoodbank.org or by postal mail at:
This Agreement was last modified on October 29, 2018.
Baltimore,
Salisbury,
Hagerstown,
Maryland Food Bank is a 501(c)(3)  |  Privacy Policy  |  Terms of Use  |  Nondiscrimination Statement  |  Governance |  State Nonprofit Disclosures
